<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Englands vvedding garment. Or A preparation to King Iames his royall coronation.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1603</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 13 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A04310</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 14421</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S109116</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99844766</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99844766</idno>
            <idno type="VID">9608</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A04310)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 9608)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1145:06)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Englands vvedding garment. Or A preparation to King Iames his royall coronation.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[14] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[Printed by R. Read] for Thomas Pauier,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1603.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Printer's name from STC.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A-B⁴ (-B4).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>James --  I, --  King of England, 1566-1625 --  Coronation --  Poetry.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:9608:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 25 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:9608:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 25 -->
            <p>ENGLANDS <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>EDDING</hi> GARMENT.</p>
            <p>Or A preparation to King <hi>IAMES</hi> his Royall Coronation.</p>
            <q>Aſpice venturo laetentur vt omniaſeclo.</q>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>French fleur-de-lis surmounted by crown</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>Imprinted at London for <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Pauier.</hi> 1603.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:9608:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 26 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:9608:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 26 -->
            <head>
               <hi>Englands wedding garment, or a</hi> preparation to King <hi>Iames</hi> his <hi>Coronation.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Eaſe ſad laments, King <hi>Brutus</hi> race,</l>
               <l>Deplore no more your bleſſed Queene,</l>
               <l>Salute your ſpring-tide welcome King,</l>
               <l>She dwels where ioyes are euer ſeene.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>When good <hi>Eliza</hi> liu'd, her winged</l>
               <l>Fame from earth did mount on hie:</l>
               <l>Now ſhe is deade, her heauen-borne ſoule,</l>
               <l>Is ſoar'd aloft aboue the skie.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Scarce had the dolefull bell rung out,</l>
               <l>Our Queene <hi>Elizaes</hi> mournefull knell,</l>
               <l>But Prince-borne <hi>Iames</hi> our King proclaim'd,</l>
               <l>Our feare ſoone paſt, and all was well.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>God ſaue King <hi>Iames,</hi> glad Engliſh crie,</l>
               <l>Let Scots the like and Iriſh ſay,</l>
               <l>His glory ſhine as beamed ſunne,</l>
               <l>Whilſt ſtarrie night ſucceedeth day.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 27 -->
               <l>We loſt a pearleſſe pearle, but we</l>
               <l>A Iem of price haue got againe,</l>
               <l>Of much more worth then can be found,</l>
               <l>In Golden mine, or Ocean maine.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Spring <hi>England</hi> ſtill with budding peace,</l>
               <l>For thou art bleſt with peaceful King,</l>
               <l>God ſaue his Grace, let voyces chaunt,</l>
               <l>Let Trumpets ſound, and Belles out ring.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>In Spring of Infant age, Prince <hi>Iames</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of Scots was croun'd their King,</l>
               <l>In Spring of yeare he comes to vs,</l>
               <l>When birds their merrie carrols ſing.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What doth the ſpringing yeare preſage,</l>
               <l>But that our Spring proclaimed King:</l>
               <l>Will ſtore of ſommer-fruites, to vs</l>
               <l>Of bliſfull peace and plentie bring.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Oh mightie Ioue, with dazled eyes,</l>
               <l>We may admire thy workes of wonder:</l>
               <l>Our Sunne begins to ſhine, when we</l>
               <l>Dread winter ſtormes and cracks of thunder.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 27 -->
               <l>When faire <hi>Eliza</hi> di'de, <hi>Apollo</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Coucht his golden treſſed head:</l>
               <l>When commons cri'd, God ſaue the King,</l>
               <l>His goldie-lockes abroad he ſpread.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>As thick as Bees in ſommer ſwarme,</l>
               <l>Or Bloſſomes hang on blooming tree:</l>
               <l>So thicke likewiſe great troupes will runne,</l>
               <l>Thy royall crowning day to ſee.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Eliza</hi> whilome was, but now</l>
               <l>King <hi>Iames</hi> is <hi>Englands</hi> cheefeſt ioy,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Ioues</hi> winged guard his throne attend,</l>
               <l>And him defend from all anoy.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What newes ſaid one? ſad newes ſaid ſome,</l>
               <l>Our Queene is ſicke, our Queene is dead:</l>
               <l>Alas, ſaid all true Engliſh harts,</l>
               <l>Then Englands ioy from vs is fled.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>But when the bright reſplendant ſunne,</l>
               <l>Had chaſt theſe darkeſome cloudes away,</l>
               <l>We cri'd aloud, God ſaue our King,</l>
               <l>Oh bleſſed time, thriſe happy day.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->
               <l>The Red Roſe and the White doe now,</l>
               <l>And ſtill we hope ſhall flouriſh long,</l>
               <l>And rare exploites of <hi>Henries</hi> race,</l>
               <l>for euer grace our Britaine ſong.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Engliſh, Scots, and Iriſh true,</l>
               <l>Of three are now combin'd in one,</l>
               <l>Their hartes a true loue knot faſt knit,</l>
               <l>All former malice now is gone.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>As viſage and the phraſe of toung,</l>
               <l>Twixt Scots and Engliſh neere agree,</l>
               <l>So guider of all hartes, their hartes</l>
               <l>Conioyne, that loyall they may bee.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>You rebell Iriſh rout, ſheath vp</l>
               <l>Your blades, ſhed teares, for mercie ſue:</l>
               <l>Your gracefull King will graunt you grace,</l>
               <l>So you to him proue iuſt and true.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Our friends are glad, our foes now feare,</l>
               <l>The Orphant ſmile, and widdow ſing:</l>
               <l>That after ſweete <hi>Elizaes</hi> death,</l>
               <l>We haue ſo wiſe, ſo kinde a King.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->
               <l>The Scholer and the Souldier ſing,</l>
               <l>The weaned childe, the beldam olde,</l>
               <l>The Cittie ſing, and Countrie both:</l>
               <l>our eares may heare, our eyes beholde.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Our Gallant Peeres, our Court, our Church,</l>
               <l>In ſweeteſt harmonie doe ſing,</l>
               <l>Accenting loud with ayrie notes,</l>
               <l>God ſaue our wiſe, and learned King,</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Scottiſh Ile doth ſtreame with teares,</l>
               <l>Shed forth for abſence of her King,</l>
               <l>The bankes of Engliſh Ile for ioy,</l>
               <l>With Ecchoes ſounding loud ſhall ring.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Be glad thou Scottiſh Ile, thy king</l>
               <l>A mightie Monarch is become,</l>
               <l>For faire <hi>Eliza</hi> now is dead,</l>
               <l>And he enioyes her Regall roome.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The beames of his reflecting eye,</l>
               <l>Shall beate vpon thy Northren coaſt,</l>
               <l>And if at neede thou call his aide,</l>
               <l>Thy King will ride to thee in poaſt.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
               <l>Let <hi>Spaine</hi> ſpight <hi>England</hi> ſtill, <hi>Infanta</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Fume, proud Pope with furie ſwell,</l>
               <l>Their boaſting threates are windie wordes,</l>
               <l>Their deedes are bred in damned hell.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The helliſh brood of damned crue,</l>
               <l>Whom Babel-Rome with poyſon fed,</l>
               <l>Did often plot, (but God ſaid no)</l>
               <l>To cut <hi>Elizaes</hi> vitall thred.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>But in deſpight of Pope and Spaine,</l>
               <l>Her houred glaſſe did all out runne,</l>
               <l>And ſhe gan quietly fall on ſleepe</l>
               <l>In peace, when her due time was come.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>What traitor plots thou haſt eſcapt,</l>
               <l>My hart doth ſigh when toung doth tell,</l>
               <l>Black poyſon and the murdering knife,</l>
               <l>Contriu'd by Hagges of darkeſt hell.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thus <hi>Ioue</hi> from heauen high did ſpeake,</l>
               <l>Touch not my King, let him alone:</l>
               <l>For he full many yeares in peace,</l>
               <l>Shall ſit vpon <hi>Elizaes</hi> throne.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
               <l>The Popiſh hoped day of glee,</l>
               <l>To them is turn'd a mourning day:</l>
               <l>God graunt their follie they may ſee,</l>
               <l>And ſeeing ſhun their owne decay.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The Pope may feare, his chaire doth reele,</l>
               <l>Although he brag with tripple crowne,</l>
               <l>An Engliſh Lion comes ere long,</l>
               <l>By force to pull him head-long downe.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Who doubts that reades thy holy booke,</l>
               <l>Compoſ'd by heau'n inſpired skill:</l>
               <l>But that thy Lion tribe the ten—</l>
               <l>Horn'd beaſt of Babel-Rome ſhall kill.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>A patron ſtout of Chriſtian faith,</l>
               <l>Shall ſway the Scepter of this Ile:</l>
               <l>When he was borne to be our Lord,</l>
               <l>The earth, the skie, and fates did ſmile.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>This fiue and fortie yeares, <hi>Eliza</hi>
               </l>
               <l>hath our ſoules with <hi>Manna</hi> fed,</l>
               <l>Moſt happie thriſe are we, that ſtill</l>
               <l>Shall feede vpon this ſacred bread.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
               <l>Our golden-age is not yet out</l>
               <l>Of date, our God yet loue vs will,</l>
               <l>His holy arch is not remou'd,</l>
               <l>His mercie ſeate is with vs ſtill.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now welcome King, thy ſubiects long,</l>
               <l>did wiſh to ſee thy princely face,</l>
               <l>That they might crie, as they were wont</l>
               <l>To doe, God ſaue your royall grace.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Thy London ſtreetes, thy <hi>Caeſar</hi> towre,</l>
               <l>Thy arched bridge doth Ecchoes ſing,</l>
               <l>And pearce the clouds with crying loud,</l>
               <l>God ſaue, God ſaue our welcome King.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now boyes and girles, both bond and free,</l>
               <l>With gladſome tongues together ſay,</l>
               <l>Oh happie we, that liue to ſee,</l>
               <l>King <hi>Iames</hi> his royall crowning day.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Let vs applaud with clapping hands,</l>
               <l>And crying loud, God ſaue our King:</l>
               <l>That earth and ayre for ioyfull noiſe,</l>
               <l>with Ecchoes chaunting loud may ring.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
               <l>Since thou wert Englands King proclaim'd,</l>
               <l>When comes the King hath beene our ſong?</l>
               <l>Now we reioyce to ſee thy face,</l>
               <l>Whom we deſir'd to ſee ſo long.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>God bleſſe thy ſtate, thy royall ſeed,</l>
               <l>Thy Princes-borne &amp; famous Queene;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Iehouah</hi> graunt all flouriſh ſtill,</l>
               <l>Like Cedar and the Laurell greene.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Let pleaſant May and ſummer dayes,</l>
               <l>Continue ſtill your during-life:</l>
               <l>Let frutefull peace, and plentie great,</l>
               <l>In Engliſh, Scottiſh Ile be rife.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Of late on ſhaddow we did gaze,</l>
               <l>And that did pleaſe our eye-ſight well,</l>
               <l>But now thy ſubſtance we may ſee,</l>
               <l>What toung our preſent ioy may tell.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>As thirſtie ſoule deſireth drinke,</l>
               <l>Or hunger ſtaru'd ſome wholeſome food,</l>
               <l>So glad are we to greete our King,</l>
               <l>The Anchor hope of Englands good.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:7"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 31 -->
               <l>And bleſſed thriſe are we by King,</l>
               <l>Who is no childe, not aged olde,</l>
               <l>But ſuch a one, as can the Helme,</l>
               <l>Of publique wealth both guide &amp; hold.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Caſt of your Sable mourning weedes,</l>
               <l>Ceaſe ſorrow, ſighes, and ſobs away,</l>
               <l>Adorne your ſelues with coloures braue,</l>
               <l>For this is Englands bridall day.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Spare now no coſt, let angels flie,</l>
               <l>As Hearaulds of your in-bread ioy,</l>
               <l>Our <hi>Caeſar</hi> now to London's come,</l>
               <l>Who will vs ſhield from all anoy.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Engliſh, French, the Dutch, and Tuſcan</l>
               <l>Braue, triumph for Englands King,</l>
               <l>Let true loue ſet your hartes on fire,</l>
               <l>Prepare rich preſents for to bring.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Beare Oliue branches in your handes,</l>
               <l>Adorne your heads with Laurell greene:</l>
               <l>Adore your <hi>Salomon</hi> of peace,</l>
               <l>Such golden dayes were neuer ſeene.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:7"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 31 -->
               <l>Let Pageants gay, let gallant ſhewes,</l>
               <l>Shew forth your inconceiued glee,</l>
               <l>That ſoueraigne Lord, by outward ſignes,</l>
               <l>Your inward loyall hearts may ſee.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Perfume the ayre with odors ſweete,</l>
               <l>Prepare rich vnguents for your King,</l>
               <l>Let muſicke ſweete ſound in your ſtreete,</l>
               <l>And voices <hi>Halleluiah</hi> ſing.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Sound Lute, ſound Harpe, let Organes ſound,</l>
               <l>Your houſes deck with rich aray:</l>
               <l>Strew paued ſtreetes with Roſes ſweete,</l>
               <l>To beautifie King <hi>Iames</hi> his day.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Let ſnow-white ſwans in Thameſis,</l>
               <l>Let birds in cages ſweetely ſing,</l>
               <l>Let Artiſtes learne them now to ſpeake,</l>
               <l>That they may ſay, God ſaue the king.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Let conduict-pipes guſh forth with wine,</l>
               <l>That cauſeth mirth, and cureth care,</l>
               <l>For Prince of peace is ſafely come,</l>
               <l>Our foes are ſicke with deadly feare.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb facs="tcp:9608:8"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 32 -->
               <l>When royall crowne of Maiden Queene,</l>
               <l>Shall circle round thy ſacred head,</l>
               <l>Great mirth and ioy our harts ſhall fill,</l>
               <l>Our griefe intoomb'd in <hi>Lethean</hi> bed.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>The rich reioyce, the poore are glad,</l>
               <l>The young and old with ioy abound,</l>
               <l>Becauſe they liue to ſee the day,</l>
               <l>Wherein king <hi>Iames</hi> our king is crown'd,</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Now milke and hony in our land</l>
               <l>Shall flowe, no cauſe of ſorrow found,</l>
               <l>The virgin pure and wedded wife,</l>
               <l>With toungs their hartie ioy ſhall ſound.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Let Angels ſtill ſupport thy throne,</l>
               <l>Let Ioue protect thee with his wing,</l>
               <l>So mirth our harts and mouth ſhall fill,</l>
               <l>Our toungs ſtill <hi>Halleluiah</hi> ſing.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Tempora foelicis ſuperos concedere vitae</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Regi, Reginae, tum ſobilique precor.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:9608:8"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 32 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
